<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>aot on Also sprach tealeg...</title>
    <link>https://www.teale.de/tags/aot/</link>
    <description>Recent content in aot on Also sprach tealeg...</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © Geoffrey J. Teale. All rights reserved. &lt;a rel=&#39;me&#39; href=&#39;https://mastodon.online/@tealeg&#39;&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2008 03:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.teale.de/tags/aot/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>On Clojure (part 6)</title>
      <link>https://www.teale.de/post/tech/programming/on-clojure-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2008 03:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.teale.de/post/tech/programming/on-clojure-6/</guid>
      <description>AOT problem solved Thanks to the swift responses of the Clojure google group I have got past my little problem. It was, of course, deceptively simple, but not clear to someone who doesn&amp;rsquo;t do Java programming much.
The problem was basically that whatever I did I could not get Clojure to recognise that the source files existed in the classpath.
When you invoke java with the -jar command line option it completely ignores the classpath (both the environment variable, or the -cp argument.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Clojure (part 5)</title>
      <link>https://www.teale.de/post/tech/programming/on-clojure-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2008 00:52:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.teale.de/post/tech/programming/on-clojure-5/</guid>
      <description>Caught on a Clojure roller-coaster I was hoping to make some decent progress this weekend with my Clojure code. The plan was to port it to the new AOT model of compilation.
However, my efforts have been frustrated by me not being able to get AOT working. I have posted my problem to the group, so hopefully there will be some solution soon.
Clojure is developing so rapidly it&amp;rsquo;s hard to keep up, I think that&amp;rsquo;s how I got into this mess with AOT.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Clojure (part 4)</title>
      <link>https://www.teale.de/post/tech/programming/on-clojure-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2008 00:22:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.teale.de/post/tech/programming/on-clojure-4/</guid>
      <description>AOT is cool, but it breaks some of what I&amp;rsquo;ve already talked about Clojure is a young language, and as such it&amp;rsquo;s developing fast. It&amp;rsquo;s an exhilarating ride to be on, but sometime it means things I&amp;rsquo;ve written change.
So, when reading my previous posts, please note that the latest revisions to Clojure include the provision of Ahead-Of-Time (AOT) compilation. This will break the compilation mechanisms I used in some of the content below.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
