<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>scheme on The ol&#39; tealeg ruminates</title>
    <link>https://www.teale.de/tags/scheme/</link>
    <description>Recent content in scheme on The ol&#39; tealeg ruminates</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2008 06:54:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.teale.de/tags/scheme/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>On Clojure (part 2)</title>
      <link>https://www.teale.de/post/tech/programming/on-clojure-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2008 06:54:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.teale.de/post/tech/programming/on-clojure-2/</guid>
      <description>Distributing QtJambi with Clojure. How to bundle up Clojure programs for distribution One of the questions I&amp;rsquo;ve seen coming up a few times is how to distribute clojure programs. The obvious answer is to build executable JAR files.
A while ago I produced a simple database application for my girlfriends recruitment business, NRecruit. I developed this using Clojure on my Arch Linux based laptop, and deployed to her MacBook running OS X Leopard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Clojure (part 1)</title>
      <link>https://www.teale.de/post/tech/programming/on-clojure-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2008 06:31:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.teale.de/post/tech/programming/on-clojure-1/</guid>
      <description>After many a dalliance with R6RS compliant(ish) Scheme implementations I have found myself inevitably drawn towards as new Lisp dialect instead. While I&amp;rsquo;m pleased to see Ikarus maturing to the state where it really is a very usable it&amp;rsquo;s not what I&amp;rsquo;ve been using to get stuff done. No, instead, I (like everyone else it seems) have fallen for Clojure.
I won&amp;rsquo;t harp on about Clojure - you can read about it everywhere, instead I&amp;rsquo;ll just make some practical notes in the following posts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s next? Ypsilon</title>
      <link>https://www.teale.de/post/tech/programming/ypsilon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2008 01:18:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.teale.de/post/tech/programming/ypsilon/</guid>
      <description>Ikarus So&amp;hellip;
For a good long while I have been tracking the Ikarus Scheme implementation. I like it because it tries to comply with R6RS, compiles to some pretty quick code and recently added 64bit support. I like it so much that I even package it and a number of related libraries for Arch Linux.
However, Ikarus has a single annoyance for me - it is not easy to extend it with C libraries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guten Morgen 2008</title>
      <link>https://www.teale.de/post/life/germany/guten-morgen-2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 15:17:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.teale.de/post/life/germany/guten-morgen-2008/</guid>
      <description>A new year So&amp;hellip; a new year.. the 30th new year of my life.
A new location A big year for me. Firstly I am now just two months away from moving to Munich with my girlfriend Nicole and I&amp;rsquo;m both terrified and excited at the same time. I&amp;rsquo;m not worried about moving to Germany - strangely I just &amp;ldquo;know&amp;rdquo; that this will be OK - I&amp;rsquo;m worried about the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ikarus ascends</title>
      <link>https://www.teale.de/post/tech/programming/ikarus-ascends/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2007 14:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.teale.de/post/tech/programming/ikarus-ascends/</guid>
      <description>If you follow scheme or lisp news in even a passing fashion you can&amp;rsquo;t have failed to notice the arrival of Ikarus Scheme, the nifty incremental, native scheme code compiler. It&amp;rsquo;s an lovely new version of scheme based around R6RS. That means it supports a nice clean library system (standardised!) and scripting in the manner of Perl, Python and Ruby.
Though it lacks the maturity and library base you&amp;rsquo;d find in chicken or PLT, it&amp;rsquo;s still a very attractive proposition, and the quality of the product thus far, combined with the nascent community feel around it has certainly got my spider sense tingling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flock...</title>
      <link>https://www.teale.de/post/tech/flock/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2007 15:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.teale.de/post/tech/flock/</guid>
      <description>Flock So I&amp;rsquo;m trying flock out again.
It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I last looked at it. All I can say is it&amp;rsquo;s improved massively. It&amp;rsquo;s actually just like Firefox with lots of lovelly extra interactions with my favourite web sites. So far so impressed.
Cider I haven&amp;rsquo;t drunk cider since university, but at the Walkabout bar in central Birmingham I was introducer to Kopperburg, Swedish cider (thank you GUADEC!) which was actually really nice.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
