<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ikarus on The ol&#39; tealeg ruminates</title>
    <link>https://www.teale.de/tags/ikarus/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ikarus on The ol&#39; tealeg ruminates</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2008 01:18:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.teale.de/tags/ikarus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s next? Ypsilon</title>
      <link>https://www.teale.de/post/tech/programming/ypsilon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2008 01:18:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.teale.de/post/tech/programming/ypsilon/</guid>
      <description>Ikarus So&amp;hellip;
For a good long while I have been tracking the Ikarus Scheme implementation. I like it because it tries to comply with R6RS, compiles to some pretty quick code and recently added 64bit support. I like it so much that I even package it and a number of related libraries for Arch Linux.
However, Ikarus has a single annoyance for me - it is not easy to extend it with C libraries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ikarus ascends</title>
      <link>https://www.teale.de/post/tech/programming/ikarus-ascends/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2007 14:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.teale.de/post/tech/programming/ikarus-ascends/</guid>
      <description>If you follow scheme or lisp news in even a passing fashion you can&amp;rsquo;t have failed to notice the arrival of Ikarus Scheme, the nifty incremental, native scheme code compiler. It&amp;rsquo;s an lovely new version of scheme based around R6RS. That means it supports a nice clean library system (standardised!) and scripting in the manner of Perl, Python and Ruby.
Though it lacks the maturity and library base you&amp;rsquo;d find in chicken or PLT, it&amp;rsquo;s still a very attractive proposition, and the quality of the product thus far, combined with the nascent community feel around it has certainly got my spider sense tingling.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
