<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>lisp on The ol&#39; tealeg ruminates</title>
    <link>https://www.teale.de/tags/lisp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in lisp on The ol&#39; tealeg ruminates</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2009 13:43:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.teale.de/tags/lisp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>On Clojure (part 7)</title>
      <link>https://www.teale.de/post/tech/programming/on-clojure-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2009 13:43:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.teale.de/post/tech/programming/on-clojure-7/</guid>
      <description>Some good Clojure news, some bad Clojure news So&amp;hellip; first the bad news.
I&amp;rsquo;ve had to drop the Qt port of my little Clojure recruitment database. I was just hitting too many problems using Qt-Jambi and it was taking too long. The client needed a working database ASAP and I wasn&amp;rsquo;t gonna get there. At the same time I also learned to use Apple&amp;rsquo;s Core Data on Mac Os X 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Clojure (part 6)</title>
      <link>https://www.teale.de/post/tech/programming/on-clojure-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2008 03:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.teale.de/post/tech/programming/on-clojure-6/</guid>
      <description>AOT problem solved Thanks to the swift responses of the Clojure google group I have got past my little problem. It was, of course, deceptively simple, but not clear to someone who doesn&amp;rsquo;t do Java programming much.
The problem was basically that whatever I did I could not get Clojure to recognise that the source files existed in the classpath.
When you invoke java with the -jar command line option it completely ignores the classpath (both the environment variable, or the -cp argument.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Clojure (part 5)</title>
      <link>https://www.teale.de/post/tech/programming/on-clojure-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2008 00:52:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.teale.de/post/tech/programming/on-clojure-5/</guid>
      <description>Caught on a Clojure roller-coaster I was hoping to make some decent progress this weekend with my Clojure code. The plan was to port it to the new AOT model of compilation.
However, my efforts have been frustrated by me not being able to get AOT working. I have posted my problem to the group, so hopefully there will be some solution soon.
Clojure is developing so rapidly it&amp;rsquo;s hard to keep up, I think that&amp;rsquo;s how I got into this mess with AOT.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Clojure (part 4)</title>
      <link>https://www.teale.de/post/tech/programming/on-clojure-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2008 00:22:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.teale.de/post/tech/programming/on-clojure-4/</guid>
      <description>AOT is cool, but it breaks some of what I&amp;rsquo;ve already talked about Clojure is a young language, and as such it&amp;rsquo;s developing fast. It&amp;rsquo;s an exhilarating ride to be on, but sometime it means things I&amp;rsquo;ve written change.
So, when reading my previous posts, please note that the latest revisions to Clojure include the provision of Ahead-Of-Time (AOT) compilation. This will break the compilation mechanisms I used in some of the content below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Clojure (part 3)</title>
      <link>https://www.teale.de/post/tech/programming/on-clojure-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2008 11:29:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.teale.de/post/tech/programming/on-clojure-3/</guid>
      <description>QT Designer with Clojure So, as promised, here&amp;rsquo;s a few notes on how I am using Qt Designer with Clojure. Some important things to remember:
 You must use Qt Designer with the QtJambi plugins installed. The easiest way to do this is to run designer.sh (Linux / UNIX / Mac OS X) or designer.bat (Windows) from the distribution folder that QtJambi came in. If you&amp;rsquo;ve got QtJambi installed as a package under Linux then you may need to check that the QtJambi plugins are correctly installed , they weren&amp;rsquo;t in my case.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Clojure (part 2)</title>
      <link>https://www.teale.de/post/tech/programming/on-clojure-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2008 06:54:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.teale.de/post/tech/programming/on-clojure-2/</guid>
      <description>Distributing QtJambi with Clojure. How to bundle up Clojure programs for distribution One of the questions I&amp;rsquo;ve seen coming up a few times is how to distribute clojure programs. The obvious answer is to build executable JAR files.
A while ago I produced a simple database application for my girlfriends recruitment business, NRecruit. I developed this using Clojure on my Arch Linux based laptop, and deployed to her MacBook running OS X Leopard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Clojure (part 1)</title>
      <link>https://www.teale.de/post/tech/programming/on-clojure-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2008 06:31:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.teale.de/post/tech/programming/on-clojure-1/</guid>
      <description>After many a dalliance with R6RS compliant(ish) Scheme implementations I have found myself inevitably drawn towards as new Lisp dialect instead. While I&amp;rsquo;m pleased to see Ikarus maturing to the state where it really is a very usable it&amp;rsquo;s not what I&amp;rsquo;ve been using to get stuff done. No, instead, I (like everyone else it seems) have fallen for Clojure.
I won&amp;rsquo;t harp on about Clojure - you can read about it everywhere, instead I&amp;rsquo;ll just make some practical notes in the following posts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guten Morgen 2008</title>
      <link>https://www.teale.de/post/life/germany/guten-morgen-2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 15:17:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.teale.de/post/life/germany/guten-morgen-2008/</guid>
      <description>A new year So&amp;hellip; a new year.. the 30th new year of my life.
A new location A big year for me. Firstly I am now just two months away from moving to Munich with my girlfriend Nicole and I&amp;rsquo;m both terrified and excited at the same time. I&amp;rsquo;m not worried about moving to Germany - strangely I just &amp;ldquo;know&amp;rdquo; that this will be OK - I&amp;rsquo;m worried about the future.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
