<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>open_solaris on Also sprach tealeg...</title>
    <link>https://www.teale.de/tags/open_solaris/</link>
    <description>Recent content in open_solaris on Also sprach tealeg...</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 May 2008 23:07:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.teale.de/tags/open_solaris/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>OpenVPN and Solaris</title>
      <link>https://www.teale.de/post/tech/opensolaris/openvpn-and-solaris/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2008 23:07:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.teale.de/post/tech/opensolaris/openvpn-and-solaris/</guid>
      <description>Solaris Joy A little more solaris joy. Mainly as a note for myself here is how to setup an OpenVPN client on OpenSolaris 2008.05:
Steps Add package repositories Add Blastwave and SunFreeWare IPS repositories to the Image Packaging System:
-bash-2.05b# pkg set-authority -O http://pkg.sunfreeware.com:9000/ Companion -bash-2.05b# pkg set-authority -O http://blastwave.network.com:10000/ Blastwave -bash-2.05b# pkg refresh Install and setup the TUN device -bash-2.05b# pkg install IPStun -bash-2.05b# add_drv tun Install OpenVPN -bash-2.05b# pkg install IPSopenvpn &amp;hellip; and now you&amp;rsquo;re ready to put your openvpn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brandz spanking new</title>
      <link>https://www.teale.de/post/tech/opensolaris/brandz-spanking-new/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2008 21:42:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.teale.de/post/tech/opensolaris/brandz-spanking-new/</guid>
      <description>Into the Solaris So, long time no Solaris talk.
I&amp;rsquo;ve not been sleeping well this last couple of weeks (ironically this seems to have a lot to do with exhausting myself during my recent trip to England), but that inevitably leads to lots of mucking around with computers in the wee hours of the morning.
The need for containers So OpenSolaris 2008.05 is on my laptop right now, and it&amp;rsquo;s a bit of surprise to find it there as I am trying to hack on some code that is destined to run on Linux.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Printing on an HP OfficeJet 6310 from Solaris</title>
      <link>https://www.teale.de/post/tech/opensolaris/printing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2007 07:21:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.teale.de/post/tech/opensolaris/printing/</guid>
      <description>I thought this would be hard but essentially it was very easy - I guess and seemed to get it right first time.
You don&amp;rsquo;t need to install CUPS as the SUNWhpijs package already supports Sun&amp;rsquo;s own print system. Simply run:
/usr/sadm/admin/bin/printmgr &amp;hellip; as root, choose PRINTER-&amp;gt;NEW ATTACHED PRINTER from the menu and then add the printer. I found it to be attached to /dev/usb/printer0 and I had to claim it was an OfficeJet 6110, but essentially everything worked perfectly and seconds later I was printing in colour on A4 paper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Indiana Wishlist</title>
      <link>https://www.teale.de/post/tech/opensolaris/indiana-wishlist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2007 15:34:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.teale.de/post/tech/opensolaris/indiana-wishlist/</guid>
      <description>OK, so many, many people will be saying many things about project Indiana before we ever see anything concrete, and then many more people will inevitably form two camps - the &amp;ldquo;Indianaphiles&amp;rdquo; and the &amp;ldquo;Indianaphobes&amp;rdquo;.
All of that is inevitable and I guess we should just enjoy the ride. However, given the scope for Indiana thus far expressed is &amp;ldquo;Make a Sun branded Solaris distribution that&amp;rsquo;s a lot more like Linux&amp;rdquo;, and that the top man is Ian Murdoch, I have exactly one wish for this project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intel HDA working under OpenSolaris</title>
      <link>https://www.teale.de/post/tech/opensolaris/intel-hda-opensolaris/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2007 12:26:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.teale.de/post/tech/opensolaris/intel-hda-opensolaris/</guid>
      <description>Another minor victory in my quest to get more familiar with OpenSolaris. I&amp;rsquo;ve upgraded to Nexenta unstable, and I noticed a package called sunwaudiohd being installed. That looked like a promising solution to the lack of audio on my OpenSolaris machine - the Intel HDA soundcard has never worked under any version I&amp;rsquo;ve used.
Sadly, the mere presence of this driver didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to fix things (it&amp;rsquo;s never that simple). A little research confirmed that it was the right driver, but that this bug had been discovered.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
