<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>emacs on Also sprach tealeg...</title>
    <link>https://www.teale.de/tags/emacs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in emacs on Also sprach tealeg...</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © Geoffrey J. Teale. All rights reserved. &lt;a rel=&#39;me&#39; href=&#39;https://mastodon.online/@tealeg&#39;&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2010 00:31:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.teale.de/tags/emacs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>HTML5 and all that</title>
      <link>https://www.teale.de/post/tech/frontend/html5-and-all-that/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2010 00:31:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.teale.de/post/tech/frontend/html5-and-all-that/</guid>
      <description>Clojure So..
Firstly a quick update re: clojure. I&amp;rsquo;m still using it, productively and occasionally frustraitedly. Most frustration comes from my lack of available time and the relative newness of the language. Now Clojure is 2 years old there are often libraries are available to do things in a way idiomatic to Clojure rather than just using Java libraries directly, however there&amp;rsquo;s no a great deal of documentation of examples for these libraries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TrueType fonts in GNU Emacs</title>
      <link>https://www.teale.de/post/tech/emacs/truetype-in-emacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2008 14:32:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.teale.de/post/tech/emacs/truetype-in-emacs/</guid>
      <description>Listing installed TrueType fonts in Emacs In this new fangled age of TrueType support in Emacs it&amp;rsquo;s really useful to know the names of the Monospace fonts installed on your system in the format that Emacs understands. If you are on a Linux/UNIX system running Xorg with fontconfig installed then add this function to your .emacs file
(defun list-monospace-truetype-fonts () &amp;#34;Provide a list of available monospaced truetype fonts on this machine&amp;#34; (interactive) (set-buffer (get-buffer-create &amp;#34;Monospaced Fonts&amp;#34;)) (call-process-shell-command &amp;#34;fc-list :spacing=mono:scalable=true family | sort&amp;#34; nil t) (setq buffer-read-only t) (switch-to-buffer-other-window (current-buffer))) You can set these fonts in a number of ways, currently I am getting the most joy using this form:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
