<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Geoffrey J. Teale</title>
    <link>https://tealeg.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Geoffrey J. Teale</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2019 15:57:18 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://tealeg.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Engineers Don&#39;t Scale</title>
      <link>https://tealeg.github.io/blog/tech/software-engineers-dont-scale/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2019 15:57:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tealeg.github.io/blog/tech/software-engineers-dont-scale/</guid>
      <description>Software Engineers don&amp;rsquo;t scale &amp;hellip; or how I learned to stop worrying and love commenting my code. NOTE: I originally published this on the Inside Heetch blog
This article, by Mathew Skelton and Manuel Pais, reminds me that, for everything that’s been made simpler in this era of cloud computing and micro-services, we’ve paid a price in terms of cognitive load. We simply need to keep more context in mind when making or evaluating any change to our code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>System Updates With Mixin</title>
      <link>https://tealeg.github.io/blog/tech/clearlinux/system-updates-with-mixin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 16:25:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tealeg.github.io/blog/tech/clearlinux/system-updates-with-mixin/</guid>
      <description>If you use ClearLinux&amp;rsquo;s mixin to add custom bundles to your installation, you will still be able to update your upstream bundles, however it will nolonger be as simple as doing a sudo swupd update. Here are the step&amp;rsquo;s you need to go through, assuming you defined your mixin repository in ~/mixin-repo:
cd ~/mixin-repo createrepo_c . sudo mixin build sudo swupd update --migrate &amp;hellip; this is at least the process I have used, and which worked for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developer Care</title>
      <link>https://tealeg.github.io/blog/tech/developer-care/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 15:57:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tealeg.github.io/blog/tech/developer-care/</guid>
      <description>Those of you who know me may be aware that at the end of August 2018, I left my job at Avocet to join a new team at Heetch.
The main allure of the role at Heetch was the chance to be part of a team deliberately set up to act as a catalyst for product developers. The concept under which we work is known as &amp;ldquo;Developer Care&amp;rdquo;, and back in November I wrote a fairly extensive blog post for Heetch about what that means and how it came to be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enabling H.264 playback in Firefox on Intel&#39;s Clearlinux</title>
      <link>https://tealeg.github.io/blog/tech/clearlinux/h264-firefox-clearlinux/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 15:41:30 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tealeg.github.io/blog/tech/clearlinux/h264-firefox-clearlinux/</guid>
      <description>In common with most Linux distros, Intel&amp;rsquo;s ClearLinux doesn&amp;rsquo;t ship H.264 decoding by default. Given the novel nature of ClearLinux there isn&amp;rsquo;t a nice off the shelf solution to this yet, so we have to use a workaround. I&amp;rsquo;ll try and find a better way to achieve this, but for now this will get H.264 video working in YouTube / Twitter etc, for now:
wget http://ffmpeg.org/releases/ffmpeg-snapshot.tar.bz2 tar xf ffmpeg-snapshot.tar.tz2 cd ffmpeg-snapshot .</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>